（影山(かげやま)飛雄(とびお)）あ
（影山･鳥養(うかい)繋心(けいしん)）短い
It's short!
（ホイスル）
（影山）うう
（日向(ひなた)翔陽(しょうよう)）ほげ
Nice save.
（影山）ナイスカバ
More importantly, Kageyama.
（日向）それより影山よう
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
We get to play one more set!
もう１セト—
やれるぞ
（白鳥沢(しらとりざわ)応援団）
白鳥沢白鳥沢
Shiratorizawa!
Episode Seven:
Obsession
Shiratorizawa!
（鷲匠(わしじょう)鍛治(たんじ)）ふがいねえ
試合やたら—
If you put in a disappointing performance,
you're going to be running back to school from here!
こから学校まで
走て帰らせからな
（天童(てんどう)覚(さとり)）俺ら１年の時
マジでやたから
We actually had to do that when I was a first-year.
It was after the third-years' farewell match.
３年の引退試合で
（五色(ごしき)工(つとむ)）ええ
（鷲匠）お前たちが
お前たちであること—
The only reason you need to win
is that you are who you are.
勝つ理由なんてそれだけだ
（鷲匠）俺が自信持て選んだ
メンバだからな
Because you're all players that I selected without hesitation.
Shiratorizawa!
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
For the final set,
（繋心）ファイナル
セト—
I'm thinking about starting with Sugawara.
スタティングは
菅原(すがわら)でいこうと思う
Shiratorizawa!
Yes, sir!
（菅原(すがわら)孝支(こうし)）はい
Shiratorizawa!
We're counting on you, Sugawara!
（菅原）大丈夫だ
緊張することなんかない
It'll be fine.
I don't have to panic.
Sugawara, give it your all!
This isn't the first time I'm going
in with the match on the line.
ピンチで入ることなんか
今までもあたんだし
Suga, give me a whole bunch of sets!
Shiratorizawa!
Shit.
My body's warmed up, but my hands are cold.
体はあたまてんのに
手が冷たい
Shiratorizawa!
（菅原）んあ
（菅原）え
けけ結婚は待てください
I-I'm not ready to get married yet!
Don't worry.
（清水(しみず)潔子(きよこ)）
大丈夫菅原と結婚の予定はない
I don't plan on marrying you, Sugawara.
You don't know that for sure!
それは分かんないだろ
I'll hold your hand for you.
（澤村(さわむら)大地(だいち)）
手なら俺が握てやるぞ
No, I'll do it.
（東峰(あずまね)旭(あさひ)）いや俺が
No! Stop! Shimizu's scent's gonna go away!
（菅原）やめろやめろ
清水のにおいが
取れちゃうだろうが
Shut up! It's not fair that you're
the only one! Let me smell it too!
（澤村）
うるさいお前だけずるい
俺のにおいを塗たくてやる
They look like they're going to be just fine.
（武田(たけだ)一鉄(いてつ)）
雰囲気は問題なしですね
Stop!
（繋心）ああ
（ホイスル）
（女子部員）
いよいよファイナルセト
It's finally the final set.
（道宮(みちみや)結(ゆい)）
あ菅原スタティング
Sugawara's starting?
I-I'm even more nervous now.
（女子部員）
な何かよけい緊張してきた
（岩泉(いわいずみ)一(はじめ)）
影山バテてきてたからな
Kageyama seems like he's pretty exhausted.
They're probably going to let him rest and
put him back in when they need him the most.
少しでも休ませて—
大事なところで
再度投入て感じか
That only works if they can make it that far.
（及川(おいかわ)徹(とおる)）
それまで踏ん張れるかだけどね
爽やか君には
荷が重すぎるんじゃない
This might be a bit much for Mr. Refreshing.
あれえ
セタ代わちゃうの
Huh? You're changing your setter?
つまんねえ
That's no fun.
If you aren't sure what to do, just set the ball to me.
迷たら俺に集めればいい
（菅原･西谷(にしのや)夕(ゆう)）う
Well, aren't you reliable! What are you, the ace?
頼もしいなエスかよこの野郎
エスだよ
Yes, I am!
We're counting on you, Tsutomu.
(れおん)）頼むぞ工
You can do it, future ace!
（山形(やまがた)隼人(はやと)）次期エス
Right!
Let's stop them here!
１本で切るぞ
Yeah!
（烏野(からすの)一同）お
（ホイスル）
（五色）う
（田中(たなか)龍之介(りゅうのすけ)）う
Sorry!
（田中）すみません
Asahi!
（菅原）旭
（東峰）でい
（ホイスル）
All right!
（武田）よし
（繋心）よし
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（谷地(やち)仁花(ひとか)）
５セト目は—
The fifth set only goes up to 15 points, right?
15点までなんですよね
（田中(たなか)冴子(さえこ)）そうなんだ
It does?
Yeah. It goes really quick.
（月島(つきしま)明光(あきてる)）
ああ本当にあという間なんだ
Hopefully they can go all the way
without Shiratorizawa catching up.
何とか点差つけられずに
いきたいな
Sugawara is a dependable setter.
（嶋田(しまだ)誠(まこと)）
菅原は堅実なセタだ
He won't fall apart!
大崩れはない
（滝ノ上(たきのうえ)祐輔(ゆうすけ)）ああ
Yeah!
（滝ノ上･嶋田）と思いたい
Or so we hope!
（白布(しらぶ)賢二郎(けんじろう)）う
It's Ushiwaka!
（菅原）ウシワカだ
（得点係）うお
（ホイスル）
All right!
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（白鳥沢一同）
しゃ
（菅原）クソ
Damn it.
Give us a good serve, Taichi!
（大平）太一(たいち)
ナイサ
（菅原）すごいプレシャだ
This pressure is insane.
（ホイスル）
（川西(かわにし)太一(たいち)）く
（西谷）前
（澤村）オライでい
Move up!
Got it!
（菅原）ふ
すまん
Sorry!
That set was low. I have to stop panicking!
（菅原）トス低い焦るな
（西谷）うふん
（天童）絶対
It's definitely going to be to the left.
（天童）レフトでしょ
（白布）く
（東峰）ふん
（西谷）アウト
It's going out!
（ホイスル）
D'oh!
The middle was covered, so you picked the
safe choice and went left for the second time.
ミドルが捕まて
２度目は安全にレフト
分かりやすいね
You're so easy to read!
Well, our left wing spikers are pretty great!
うちのレフトは優秀なんでね
I want to break your heart in two!
心へし折りたい
（菅原）
うちのスパイカは強い
We have good spikers.
I know that more than anyone.
俺が一番分かてる
（ホイスル）
Give us a good serve, Asahi!
（菅原）旭ナイサ
（東峰）フゥ
（白布）く
（天童）ぐ
（菅原）オライ
Got it!
Our team is plenty good.
（菅原）うちの連中は
ちゃんと強い
But...
Nishinoya!
（菅原）西谷
（天童）うん
...we don't stop there!
（菅原）そこで止まるな
They're having the libero set while doing
a synchronized attack with everyone else?!
リベロのセトアプからの—
リベロ以外全員シンクロ
Asahi!
（西谷）
旭さんまだ時間あるんで—
There's still a little time left,
so could you hit some of my sets?
俺のトス
打てもらえませんか
（田中）
ノヤさん俺にも打たしてくれ
Noya! Let me hit a few too!
Sounds good, Ryuu!
おうもちろんだぜ龍(りゅう)
Oh, me too.
（菅原）ああ俺も
（３人）あ
あ上げてくれるんすか
スガさんあざす
You'll throw them up for us, Suga?
That'll be perfect!
Um, not exactly.
ああ違う違う
（田中･東峰･西谷）え
（西谷）う
I'm gonna spike.
（菅原）打つほう
（五色）うう
（ホイスル）
（日向･影山）おお
（一同）おしゃ
All right!
All of them...
（川西）全員て
They didn't leave anyone back to dig out a block?
（瀬見(せみ)英太(えいた)）
ブロクフォロ１人もなしかよ
（冴子）よしゃ
（谷地）よし
Yeah!
大崩れしなければいいとかいう
話じゃなかたですね
Looks like we didn't have to worry about him falling apart.
Nice one, Suga! I love ya!
Looks like our minds were a bit closed off.
俺らの頭が守りに入てたな
My weapon is my reliability.
（菅原）俺の武器は堅実さ
But...
I can do new things too!
俺にも新しいことができる
Karasuno                    Shiratorizawa
Yes! We scored back-to-back points!
よしブレイクだ
Nice spike, Suga!
（澤村）スガナイスキ
（菅原）ああ
Yeah!
（東峰）やたな
We did it!
Satori!
（コチ）覚
（コチ）何回言わせんだ
直感だけで跳ぶんじゃない
How many times do I have to tell you?!
Don't jump just on instinct!
でも俺１人の直感だけで
何点も取てますよ
But I've scored tons of points just on instinct.
（コチ）
いつもそうとは限らないだろ
That's not always going to work.
There are limits to your individual skills.
個人技には限界があるんだ
If it doesn't feel good to me, there's no point.
（天童）今が気持ちよくなきゃ
意味ないですもん
（コチ）ハァ
Practice always stops when Tendou's around.
（部員）天童がいると
いちいち練習が止まるんだよな
Though it's nice to be able to rest.
（部員）休めていいけど
Actually, he's kinda scary.
（部員）
ていうか何か怖いよな天童
You never know what he's thinking.
何考えてるか
分かんない感じがさ
I know, right?
だよな
I just want to play volleyball that makes me feel good.
（天童）俺は—
俺が気持ちのいいバレが
やりたいんです
As long as you can score, I don't have any complaints.
（鷲匠）点が取れるなら
何の文句もねえよ
Keep on breaking them!
（天童）バキバキに折れ
何を
What, you say?
心をだよ
Their hearts...
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Wakatoshi, did you catch Sadako
when it was on last week?
（天童）若利(わかとし)君先週
「サダ子(こ)」やてたの見た
（牛島(うしじま)若利(わかとし)）見てない
I didn't.
It's scary, but I ended up watching it because
the leading actress, Brunhilde Reiko, is super cute!
怖いんだけどさ—
主演のブリュンヒルデ玲子(れいこ)—
めちゃかわいいから
見ちゃたよねえ
（牛島）そうか
I see.
Isn't Brunhilde Reiko cute?
The only person who could excitedly talk to Wakatoshi about a TV show is Satori.
若利とテレビの話題で
盛り上がれるのは覚だけだな
I don't know who that is.
But you know, I'm not sure about the other girl,
at least in my opinion.
One of them doesn't look too excited, no matter how you look at it.
盛り上がてはない
どう見ても
若利君て何やてても
楽しそうじゃないよね
You never look like you're having
fun doing anything, Wakatoshi.
That's so rude!
おい失礼だな
Why did you start playing volleyball?
若利君は何でバレ始めたの
I learned it from my father for a little while.
父親に少しの間教わた
Huh...
（天童）へえ
Ushijima
（母親）左利きは早いうちに—
I thought it'd be better to fix his left-handedness early on.
矯正したほうが
いいんじゃないかと思て
（父親）
えいやそんなことないて
What? No, that's not necessary.
We've always done that in our household.
（祖母）うちでは昔から
そうしているしね
（祖母･母親）うん
（父親）あのでもすいません
I'm sorry, but please... anything but that.
それだけは
（牛島）ん
The fact that he's different from other people
will probably become his source of strength.
（父親）少しでも人と違うものを
持ているというのは—
きとこの子の力になるので
I won't complain about anything else!
他のことには
口を出しませんから
Did your dad play volleyball?
（天童）父ちゃんは選手
Yeah, he played on a second division team.
（牛島）
ああ２部リグの選手だた
But apparently, before he got married,
he got injured quite often and retired.
結婚より前に
ケガが多くて引退してしまたが
Really? What's his name?
へえ何て選手
Utsui Takashi.
（牛島）空井(うつい)崇(たかし)
Never heard of him.
知らないていうか
牛島じゃないんだね
Wait, so his name isn't Ushijima?
He married into my mother's family.
（牛島）婿養子だたからな
Though my parents got divorced a while back.
両親はだいぶ前に離婚したが
Huh? Oh, sorry.
えごめん
（牛島）んいや
It's fine.
Do you ever see him?
会たりすんの
（牛島）いや今は海外にいる
No. He's overseas right now.
ひいかけ
Wow, that's so cool!
You know, if you become a star,
your dad will probably watch you too.
じゃあさ若利君
スタになれば父ちゃんも見るね
Perhaps.
そうだな
I think back in your dad's time,
Shiratorizawa won nationals.
若利のお父さんの代に—
白鳥沢は全国制覇を
果たしたんだたはず
Seriously?! That's awesome!
マジすげえじゃん
じゃあ父ちゃんみたく
なりたい的な
So, did you want to be like your dad?
No, not really.
いや特には
I see.
あそう
（牛島）ただ
It's just...
Our ace was literally the best ace in Japan.
（父親）俺たちのエスは
文字どおり日本一のエスでな
（牛島）う
Back then, he was 190 cm tall.
（父親）
当時の身長は190センチ
He was a third-year, yet he was still growing.
高校３年でまだ伸びていた
But that wasn't why he was good.
でも体格だけじゃなく—
He made you think that if you set the ball to him,
he would never disappoint you.
“こいつに上げれば
絶対に決めてくれる”
そう思わせてくれるヤツだた
He would make it work out somehow.
“こいつは何かやてくれる”
（父親）てな
こうワクワクすんだよな
It made you get all excited.
I wanted to be like that.
（牛島）
そういうふうになりたいと思た
（五色）うう
（ホイスル）
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
（烏野一同）
しゃ
All right!
Why don't you do that too, Kageyama?
影山もやれば
I can't.
無理です
I haven't practiced that.
俺は練習してません
I haven't practiced working with Nishinoya.
西谷さんと合わせる練習を
（ブザ
Already? That was fast!
（冴子）早(はや)もう
Well, once someone takes the lead
in the fifth set, it's over in no time.
５セト目は
点差つけられたら—
あちゅう間だしな
Take those points back!
（鷲匠）取り返せ以上
That's all.
Yes, sir!
（部員たち）はい
烏野ムチャな攻撃してくるな
Karasuno sure does some reckless attacks.
Yeah.
ああリベロが上げて—
I've never seen a libero set and then
everyone else comes in to attack.
それ以外全員で攻撃なんて
初めて見た
You're impressed by that,
but you don't like their number ten, huh?
今のには感心するのに
10番はイヤなんだね
I'm guessing you don't like him
because he's so enigmatic, right?
若利君が
10番をイヤだと思うのは—
得体が知れないからじゃない
Things you can't understand are scary, aren't they?
よく分からないものて
怖いじゃん
They're not scary.
怖くない
（天童）いやいや
No, I mean they're sorta creepy.
ほら“何かやだな”て
思うてこと
If anything, the feeling of something being sorta creepy must be a new feeling for you, huh?
少なくとも“何かやだな”は—
若利君には
新しい感覚なんじゃない
（ブザ
Do it again, Asahi!
（ホイスル）
（西谷）旭さんもう１本
あうく
（ホイスル）
（嶋田）おお
（滝ノ上）こ
Th-This time, it hit the net on our side!
今度はこちがネトインだ
Karasuno                    Shiratorizawa
（ホイスル）
Do that again!
（澤村）もう１本だ
（五色）う
Yes! He broke through!
よし崩した
美しいねえ
How beautiful.
（牛島）てい
（ホイスル）
All right!
（白鳥沢一同）よしゃ
（父親）少しでも人と違うものを
持ているというのは—
The fact that he's different from other people
will probably become his source of strength.
きとこの子の力になるので
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（五色）
牛島さんナイサ１本
Give us a good serve again, Ushijima!
Wakatoshi!
（大平）
若利強烈なの頼むぞ
We're counting on you to hit a hard one!
（ホイスル）
（３人）さ来い
Bring it!
（東峰）う
（ホイスル）
Be Courageous Warriors
Nice spike, Ushijima!
Sorry!
すまん
（澤村）次１本
We'll get the next one!
You have to stop him here!
ここで切れよ
If you don't, it's gonna get rough!
これ以上ノセるとまずいぞ
（ホイスル）
（牛島）く
Daichi!
（西谷）大地さん
（澤村）ぐは
Suga, get the last hit!
スガラスト
（白布）がく
（影山）
セタに取らせたうまい
He got the setter to receive it. Nice!
天童さん
（天童）あいよ
Tendou!
Righto!
（天童）ふほい
Hup.
（牛島）ふん
（ホイスル）
（西谷）あ今
I thought he'd definitely hit to me,
given which way his body was facing,
体の向きからして—
絶対俺のほうに
打てくると思た
but he changed his aim right as he hit it.
寸前でコスを—
打ち変えやがた
Join a good team.
（父親）
強いチムに入るといい
Nice set, me!
強くなれる環境には
強いヤツやおもしろいヤツが集まる
Talented and interesting players gather in a good environment.
Nice aim!
And if you become better, you'll be
able to go up against all kinds of people.
そして強くなれば
いろんなヤツと戦える
Talented players, weird players, and new players.
強いヤツ変なヤツ新しいヤツ
I'm sure that they'll make you better.
そいつらはきと
お前を強くしてくれる
（牛島）ふ
Well, that's only if you want to continue playing volleyball.
（父親）いやまあ
お前がバレを続けたいと
思たらの話だけど
It doesn't matter how, but if you end up liking volleyball in some way, it'll make me happy.
どういう形でも—
お前がバレを好きに
なてくれたらうれしい
That was some really nice aim.
キレキレなコスだな若利
さすがだ
It was amazing.
To borrow Tendou's words for a second...
（牛島）
天童の言葉を借りると
I'm starting to get into it!
ノてきた
（天童）うおお
（ホイスル）
（牛島）ふん
（澤村･西谷）アウト
It's going out!
（ホイスル）
（白鳥沢一同）よしゃ
All right!
（観客）白鳥沢逆転
Shiratorizawa took back the lead!
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
Wakatoshi's serves can still be pretty hit-or-miss,
（斉藤(さいとう)明(あきら)）若利のサブは—
まだまだ
調子にムラがありますが—
but he's doing amazingly today.
今日はいつになくいいですね
うちのエスに
火つけちゃたねえ
Looks like you set our ace on fire.
（菅原）ん
（ホイスル）
拾た
He got it!
（澤村）ぐ返せラスト
Get the ball back over the net!
Here's our chance to score!
（山形）チャンスボル
（天童）そあ
（谷地）ああ
（明光）後ろからウシワカ
Ushiwaka from the back row?
（牛島）く
I touched it!
（月島(つきしま)蛍(けい)）ワンタチ
（天童･白布）チ
（ホイスル）
（応援団員）ナイスキ牛島
Be Courageous Warriors
Nice spike, Ushijima!
うとうしい
So annoying...
Ushijima!
Thanks!
どうも
（白布･天童）くう
That was close.
（武田）惜しかたですね
Usually, you want to jump up when the spiker looks
like they're going to hit it right in front of you,
普通なら目の前の
打てきそうな—
スパイカに
飛びつきたくなるけど—
but Tsukishima typically doesn't fall for decoys.
月島が基本的に
おとりにつられることはない
So he's read blocking.
リドブロクですね
（繋心）トスが上がた先に
必ず月島は来る
Wherever the set goes, Tsukishima will be there.
Having a wall pop up in front of you no matter
what must be extremely discomforting.
目の前に必ず
壁があるていう—
それだけの事実が
どれだけ不快か
And if that keeps happening over the course of five sets,
それを５セトの間
ずと続けられたら—
it'll end up being pretty stressful
for even the most unflappable person.
どんな無神経なヤツだて
相当なストレスになてるよ
（ホイスル）
（牛島）でい
（東峰）前
（澤村）く
In front!
We can score here!
（山形）チャンスボルうう
（白布）ふ
（天童）でい
What?!
You're not getting through.
（月島）たたき落とせはしないか
（山形）うもかいもかい
Let's try again!
（白布）えい
（月島）はう
（大平）てい
ワンチ
I touched it!
（日向）青根(あおね)さんみてえ
He's just like Aone!
ナイスワンタチ
Nice contact!
Damn, Tsukki is so freaking reliable!
ヤベえツキ超心強い
Here's our chance!
チャンスボル
He read our moves?!
（菅原）読まれてる
（天童）ブロクが待ち構えてる
真ん中使うの怖いよね
Setting to the middle blocker when there's
a block waiting is scary, right? I get it.
分かるよだからレフトだよね
うんうん分かるよ
That's why you set to the left wing spiker. Yep. Totally understandable.
（田中）う
ぐ
（山形）う
Let's...
（天童）もういちょ
go...
again!
His concentration is amazing.
（明光）すごい集中だ
With such a long rally and their exhaustion,
長いラリと疲労で—
it wouldn't be weird if their bodies
were moving faster than their minds.
頭より体が先に動いてしまても
おかしくないのに—
But he grasps only the necessary information.
必要な情報だけをすくい取る
（牛島）ふん
（月島）う
（澤村）ぐう
（ホイスル）
Nice aim...
ナイスコス
アウト
It's out?!
Sorry.
すまん
（五色）ドドンマイです
I-It's fine.
He made a mistake?! So lucky!
ミスラキ
Luck has nothing to do with it!
ラキじゃねえぜ
（冴子）ん
That mistake is proof of how hard he was trying to avoid the block!
（嶋田）ブロクを避けたいて
意識が強く働いた証拠だ
（谷地）あれ
Huh?
What? It was overturned?
ええオバコル
What?
何
The ball just barely hit the block.
ブロクが
ちょと触てたんだ
It's Shiratorizawa's point.
白鳥沢の得点だよ
Seriously?!
マジか
They're on the right track, though!
でもいい傾向じゃん
切り替え切り替え
Get refocused, guys!
（山口(やまぐち)忠(ただし)）あ
Um...
あの
（繋心）あ
There's something wrong with his hand.
（影山）アイツ手変です
Damn it.
（月島）クソ
（白布）ああ
What?
何
It must've been cut when you touched Ushiwaka's spike.
ウシワカのスパイクに
触た時に切れたんだ
I hope that's the extent of it...
（繋心）
だけで済んでればいいが
Narita!
（繋心）成田(なりた)
（成田一仁(かずひと)）あはい
Y-Yes, sir!
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（月島）クソ
こんな時に
Damn. Talk about bad timing.
幸い小指痛みさえ我慢すれば—
Thankfully, it was just my pinky. If I can just endure the pain...
血て
どのくらいで止まるんだ
How long until it stops bleeding?
If we just tape it up...
テピングで
ガチガチに固めれば—
The next rotation will have Hinata in the front row.
次のロテで日向が前衛だ
I need to figure something out by then.
何とかその間に
Get him to the infirmary.
（繋心）とりあえず
医務室だ
Oh dear. He got hurt?
（及川）ありゃりゃケガ
Four-eyes leaving this late in the match is going to hurt.
この終盤で
あのメガネの離脱は痛すぎるな
You'd better buy me some time!
ちゃんと時間稼いでよ
ぐお前が戻てきた時には—
By the time you get back,
we'll already be bound for nationals!
もう全国行き決まてから
おい集中し直し
All right! Concentrate!
（部員たち）うす
Right!
Kazuhito! You're not alone in your blocks!
一仁ブロクは
単品じゃねえからな
I'll be right behind you!
後ろには俺がいる
（成田）うん
Right!
Don't hold back and go for it, just like we practiced!
練習どおり遠慮せずに入てこい
Right!
Looks like he had to leave.
アイツ引込んじゃたねえ
But we're not gonna hold back.
でも手は抜かないよ
Of course not.
（牛島）もちろんだ
（明光）蛍
Kei!
What are you doing here?
（月島）兄ちゃん
何でいるんだよ知てたけど
Though I knew you were.
（明光）弟の雄姿を見に来たに
決まてんだろ
I came to see my younger brother fight bravely, of course!
Though it looks like you're not going to die from that.
その様子だと死にはしないな
What do you mean, "die"?
（月島）死て何
Even if I'm not dead,
I'm being pretty useless when it matters most.
生きてても肝心なところで
役立たずだけどね
On the other hand, I'm pretty tired after playing five sets,
so it's sort of nice to be able to rest.
まあでも５セトなんて
疲れるし—
休めてちょうどいいよ
手痛いけど
Even though my hand hurts.
"My teammates will win, even if I leave them be!"
（明光）“俺の仲間は
放といても勝つ”
You just have to believe that.
そんくらい信じとけばいいんだ
Don't worry.
（清水）心配しないで
（月島）あ
戻てきたら負けてた
なんてこと絶対ないから
You don't have to worry about
going back just to see them lose.
Japanese National High School Volleyball Tournament
（澤村）月島があんな顔
するようになてたなんてな
I guess Tsukishima can make that kind of face now.
If we don't show them what
we're made of now, we never will!
ここで根性見せずに
いつ見せんだよ
（ホイスル）
Bring it.
来い
（東峰）来い
Bring it.
（西谷）来い
（西谷･澤村･東峰）
さ来い
Bring it!
（澤村）う
（菅原）大地ナイス
Nice, Daichi!
（成田）センタ
Center!
（天童）ふ
あまたあれやる
He's doing it again!
I hate doing setter dumps... because I'm scared of them.
（菅原）
俺はツアタクは嫌いだ
怖いから
スパイクもなし
It's the same with spikes.
I can't risk messing up if I try to step outside my usual role.
本業以外にしゃしゃり出て—
もしミスたらと思うと
勝負できない
Fly
でも—
But you have to risk something if you want a reward!
勝負に出なきゃ勝利もない
Karasuno is only Karasuno when
we're persistently attacking!
執ように攻めてこそ烏野
Right!
ライト
Full-team synchronized attack!
（烏野一同）
シンクロ攻撃オル
Go!
（３人）いけ
（子供）こちのチム
来んなよ天童
Don't join to our team, Tendou!
Monsters aren't allowed on human teams!
（子供）妖怪は人間のチムには
入れないんだぞ
Yeah, he does look like a monster.
（子供）確かに妖怪ぽい
（ホイスル）
Good job reading their play, Satori.
よく読んだな覚
It was just a hunch.
（天童）うん勘
（子供）ふえい
（子供）あああ
（天童）はあ
Ever since I first saw that expression,
（天童）
あの顔を見た瞬間から—
I haven't been satisfied by just deflecting the ball.
俺はワンタチで
満足なんかできない
What're you doing, Tendou?
（瀬見）天童何してんの
Look at this.
（天童）
見てよ俺の昔の髪型
Isn't my haircut from when I was a kid super fashionable?
超おしゃれじゃない
Whoa, is that really you?! It's the same as Tsutomu's!
（瀬見）
おいマジかよ工かよ
Did you call?
（五色）呼びましたか
（瀬見）やめとけ
Don't look! You'll end up wanting to shave your head!
見たら
頭丸めたくなるぞ
Episode Eight:
An Annoying Guy
次回「ハイキュ」
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
"An Annoying Guy."